hamiltonbroadway.com 2019-09-23

# EU Privacy Policy - Hamilton Official Site – Hamilton Official Site

Hamilton Uptown Limited Liability Company of 1501 Broadway, 24th Floor, New York, NY 10036 (“Hamilton,” “we” or “us”) respects your privacy. We created this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy and to help you understand how your information is collected and used.

This Privacy Policy explains our practices regarding information collection and usage solely for our website for _Hamilton: An American Musical_ accessible at [www.hamiltonmusical.com](https://hamiltonmusical.com/) (the “Website”). This Privacy Policy applies only to the Website and does not govern any other websites, applications or services, unless it appears on such website, application or service.

By using or accessing the Website, you agree that you have read and understood our Privacy Policy. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO US USING YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION IN THE MANNER SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE WEBSITE.

**IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA (“EEA”):** For the purposes of the European General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), Hamilton shall be considered the data controller of your personally identifiable information. Please also see the section of this Privacy Policy entitled “ _Additional Information and Rights applicable to Individuals Located in the EEA_ ”, which sets out the additional information that the GDPR requires us to provide to you to explain our processing activities and your rights in relation to those activities.  

**Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect**

Hamilton collects personally identifiable information about you that you voluntarily submit to us. We may collect this information in a variety of ways, including without limitation when you subscribe to our newsletter, request theater directions or fill out a form on the Website. The personally identifiable information which you may voluntarily provide to us or we may otherwise collect or access through the Website includes:

  * Your name, e-mail address and age.
  * Your location (if we have your consent, where required by law).
  * Information about you contained in communications between you and us (e.g., emails).</span  

  * Any content you provide to the Website.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information That We Collect  **

When you visit the Website, we may automatically collect certain non-identifying information about you, such as the computer operating system or mobile device that you use to access the Website, your Internet Protocol address, your browser type and settings, the date and time that you access the Website, the domain name of the website from which you arrived to the Website, links that you click on within the Website, any other activity of yours on the Website and other technical information that assists us in improving the Website.  Note, in some jurisdictions (including European member states), your Internet Protocol address may be considered personally identifiable information. 

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

Our Sites may use certain cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files and other technologies. Please see our [Cookie Policy ](https://hamiltonmusical.com/eu-cookie-policy/)to find out more about the cookies and other technologies we use, the purposes for which we use them and how to manage, block or delete them.

**How We Use Your Information**

In addition to other specific uses that we describe in this Privacy Policy, we may use any information that we collect (including personally and non-personally identifiable information) for the following purposes:

  * **Feedback:** From time to time, we may invite you to provide feedback about us or our products and services. We will use your personal information contained in your feedback or survey response to help us improve the quality of service provided by our personnel. We also use your feedback to monitor the quality of our products and services and to assist with the selection of future products and services. 
  * **Customer services:** When you submit an enquiry to us, whether through the Website or otherwise, we use your information to enable us to manage and respond to your enquiries and requests. We may also contact you with service messages (e.g., changes/updates to features of our services which may affect you and technical and security notices) Your access to and use of our Website, including any secure areas, is subject to our [Terms of Use](https://hamiltonmusical.com/eu-terms/).
  * **Promotions:** From time to time, we may run prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions on our Website. For the purposes of administering such promotions, we may process your name, contact details (including email address, postal address and/or telephone number, as applicable), social media handle (if relevant) and any other personal information volunteered by you in your promotion entry.
  * **Marketing activities:** We use your information to send you updates (e.g., relating to our products, services, special offers, features, and promotions), marketing materials and other information from time to time via email or other forms of electronic communication, for which you will have the opportunity to either opt-in or opt-out in accordance with applicable law. **If you are located within the EEA:** We will only send you marketing communications by email where you have consented to receive such communications, or where we have another lawful right to do so under applicable law.
  * **Insight and analysis:** We use your information to monitor metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns. This information is used to create insights about our visitors’ use of our Website. Where we have your consent to do so (where required by applicable law), we will also use your location data for insight and analysis purposes. By using this information, we are able to measure the effectiveness of our content and how visitors use our Website and our products and services. This allows us to learn what features and functionality of our Website are most attractive to our visitors, which parts of our Website are the most interesting and what kind of features and functionalities our visitors and clients like to see.
  * **Diagnostics and maintenance:** We use your information to help us diagnose or fix technology problems with the Website and to provide, improve, test, and monitor the effectiveness of the Website.
  * **Business administration and legal compliance:** We use your information for business administration and legal compliance purposes, including without limitation, to comply with our legal obligations, to enforce our legal rights, to protect the rights of third parties, and in connection with a business transition such as a merger, reorganisation, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets.

**Disclosure Of Your Information**

We will not disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent, except as set forth below or provided elsewhere in this Privacy Policy:

  * We may disclose your personally identifiable information to our vendors, subcontractors, and partners, and other third parties who provide services to us. However, they are only permitted to access your information in connection with performing such services and are not authorized by us to use the information for their own benefit.
  * We may disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties who provide, or assist us in providing, products and services that are offered on the Website. The use of your information by such third parties will be subject to the privacy policies of such third parties once such information is transferred. 
  * We may disclose (with your consent if you are an EU resident) your personally identifiable information to our partners that provide products and services or technologies that we believe may be of interest to you. The use of your information by our partners and their vendors and contractors will be subject to the privacy policies of our partners once such information is transferred.
  * We may disclose your personally identifiable information to protect the safety, rights, or property of the public, any person, or Hamilton; to investigate, prevent, or otherwise address suspected fraud or other violations of any law, rule or regulation or the Terms of Use for the Website; to detect, prevent or otherwise address security or technical issues; or as we believe is required by law, regulation, or legal process.
  * We do not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties; provided, however, we may engage in a merger, acquisition, disposition, change of control, bankruptcy, dissolution, reorganization, or similar transaction or proceeding that involves the transfer of your information.

We may share non-personally identifiable information or generic aggregated demographic information with our partners or other third parties for any purpose.

**Security**

The security of your information is very important to us. We attempt to provide for the secure storage of your information by using commercially reasonable safeguards. Unfortunately, due to the inherent nature of the Internet and online communications, we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us or guarantee that information on the Website or our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties such as hackers. Your use of the Website demonstrates your assumption of this risk. All of our employees, workers and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal data on our behalf), who have access to, and are associated with, the processing of personally identifiable information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of the personally identifiable information of all visitors to the Website and all users of our products and services.

**Other Services, Websites and Applications**

The Website may integrate third-party services and content and may contain links to third-party websites and applications. Functionality on the Website may also permit interactions between the Website and a third-party website or feature. For example, the Website may include a feature that enables you to share content from the Website with a third party, which may be publicly posted on that third party’s service or application. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these third-party services, websites and applications, and we do not endorse or promote such third-party websites, applications and services. This Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use do not apply to any third-party service, website or application. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party service, website or application or service, including those that are integrated in the Website or have a link on the Website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. When you link away from our Website, you do so at your own risk.  

**Social Media**

The Website may contain links to our presence on various social media platforms. As we do not operate or control such platforms, this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use do not apply to your use of such platforms. In addition, you should be aware that personally identifiable information which you voluntarily include and transmit online in a publicly accessible blog, social network or other social media platform may be viewed and used by others. We are unable to control such uses of your personally identifiable information, and by using such services you assume the risk that the personally identifiable information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties.

**User Communication With Us**

Any material or communications transmit to us by email, including, without limitation, any information, photographs, data, questions, comments, or suggestions, will be treated as non-confidential and non-proprietary and may be used by us for any purpose, including, without limitation, reproduction, disclosure, transmission, publication, broadcast and posting. 

**Protection for Children**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13. The Website and its content are not directed at children under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [info@hamiltonmusical.com](mailto:info@hamiltonmusical.com).

**IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EEA:** Our Website and the commercial products and services that we offer are not specifically targeted at children, although we appreciate that they may appeal to children. If you are under the age of 18, we ask that you obtain your parent’s or guardian’s consent before submitting any personal information to us or requesting any products or services from us. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under 18, please ensure that you supervise your child’s use of our Website and our products and services and ensure they obtain your consent before submitting any personal information to us or requesting any products or services from us. For the purpose of safeguarding the rights, interests and freedoms of children, we may ask you to verify your age in order to continue using our Website and/or any of our products and services you may have requested.

**Rights of California Residents**

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request and obtain from us a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. Requests may be made only once a year and are free of charge.

**Additional Information and Rights Applicable to Individuals Located in the EEA**

**Legal basis for processing**

Under the GDPR, we are required to tell you the legal basis we are relying on to process your personally identifiable information for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

Where your information is completely anonymized, we do not require a legal basis to use it as the information will no longer constitute personally identifiable information that is regulated under data protection laws. However, our collection and use of such anonymized information may be subject to other laws where your consent is required. Please see the section entitled “ _Cookies and Similar Technologies_ ” above for further details.

The below table explains our legal basis for processing your personally identifiable information, in particular for the purposes set out in the “ _How We Use Your Information_ ” section above:

PURPOSE OF PROCESSING | LEGAL BASIS  
---|---  
Feedback  |  It is in our legitimate interest to use the personally identifiable information provided by you in your feedback or survey response for the purposes of improving our products and services and the quality of service provided by our personnel.   
Customer services  |  It is necessary for us to use your personally identifiable information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you or it is in our legitimate interest or a third party’s legitimate interest to use personally identifiable information in such a way to ensure that we provide the products and services you have requested and respond to your requests and enquiries in an effective and efficient way.   
Promotions  |  It is necessary for us to use your personally identifiable information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you (e.g. the terms and conditions applicable to the promotion to which you may be asked to agree as a condition of entry) or it is in our legitimate interest to use your personally identifiable information to enable you to participate in any prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions we may run from time to time.   
Marketing Activities  |  We will only send you marketing communications by email and other electronic means where you have consented to receive such communications by that method, or where we have another lawful right to do so. We will only pass your personally identifiable information to third parties for their own marketing purposes where you have consented.   
Insight and analysis  |  It is in our legitimate interest to use your personally identifiable information for insight and analysis purposes to ensure that we provide good quality products and services to you and our other customers.   
Diagnostics  |  It is in our legitimate interest to use the personally identifiable information provided by you in relation to any customer service or technology issue you may contact us about for the purposes of improving our Website, our products and services and the quality of the service provided by our personnel.   
Business administration and legal compliance  |  Where we use your personally identifiable information in connection with a business transition, to enforce our legal rights or to protect the rights of third parties, it is in our legitimate interest to do so. We have a legal obligation to use your personally identifiable information to comply with any legal obligations imposed on us, such as a court order.   
  
**How we obtain your consent**

Where our use of your personally identifiable information requires your consent, you can provide such consent either at the time we collect your personally identifiable information following the instructions provided or by informing us using our details in the “Contact” section below.

**Duration of processing**

Regarding personally identifiable information we have processed in connection with the supply of our products and services to any person or organization, we will retain personally identifiable information relevant to that supply of products or services for six years from the date of supply and in compliance with our obligations under the GDPR (or similar legislation around the world). We may then destroy such files without further notice or liability.

Regarding any other personally identifiable information we have processed, we will retain relevant personally identifiable information for three years from the date of our last interaction with the relevant person or organization and in compliance with our obligations under the GDPR (or similar legislation around the world). We may then destroy such files without further notice or liability.

If any personally identifiable information is only useful for a short period (e.g. for a specific marketing campaign), we may delete it at the end of that period.

**Sharing Personally Identifiable Information**

We will only share personally identifiable information with others when we are legally permitted to do so. When we share personally identifiable information with others, we put contractual arrangements and security mechanisms in place to protect the personally identifiable information and to comply with our data protection, confidentiality and security standards. When processing your personal information we may need to share it with third parties as follows:

**_Other organizations within our group of companies:_** We may share your personally identifiable information with other organizations within our group of companies where necessary for administrative purposes or where those organizations assist us in the provision of our products and services.

**_Third-party organizations that provide applications/functionality, data processing or IT services:_** We use third parties to support us in providing our products and services and to help provide, run and manage our internal IT systems. Such third parties may include, for example, providers of information technology, cloud based software as a service providers, identity management, website hosting and management, data analysis, data back-up, security and storage services. The servers powering and facilitating that cloud infrastructure are located in secure data centres around the world, and personally identifiable information may be stored in any one of them.

**_Third-party email marketing and CRM specialists:_** We share personally identifiable information with specialist suppliers who assist us in managing our marketing database and sending out our email marketing communications to our subscribers.

**_Third-party organizations that assist us with the administration of our promotions:_** We share personally identifiable information with specialist suppliers who assist us in administering our competitions, prize draws and other promotions.

_**Auditors, lawyers, accountants and other professional advisers:**_ We share personally identifiable information with professional services firms who advise and assist us in relation to the lawful and effective management of our organization and in relation to any disputes we become involved in.

**_Law enforcement or other government and regulatory agencies:_** We may share personally identifiable information with law enforcement or other government and regulatory agencies or other third parties as required by, and in accordance with, applicable law or regulation.

**Transfers of your Personally Identifiable Information Outside the EEA**

We are a U.S. organization and many of our suppliers are U.S. organizations. Therefore when you submit personally identifiable information through our Sites, your personally identifiable information will be transferred to the United States of America where it will be stored and processed by us and, where applicable, our suppliers and other third parties referred to in this Privacy Policy for the purposes specified in this Privacy Policy. The laws of the United States of America may not offer the same standard of legal protection for your personally identifiable information that you enjoy in your own country. However, we will comply with our legal and regulatory obligations in relation to your personally identifiable information including having a lawful basis for transferring your personally identifiable information and putting appropriate safeguards in place to ensure an adequate level of protection for your personally identifiable information where it is transferred outside the EEA. Where we are transferring, storing or processing your personally identifiable information outside the EEA not strictly for the purpose of providing our services (e.g. to send you marketing), we shall only do so with your consent.

**Your Rights**

You have the following rights in relation to the personally identifiable information we hold about you:

_**Your right of access:**_ If you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your personally identifiable information and, if so, provide you with a copy of that personally identifiable information (along with certain other details). If you require additional copies, we may charge a reasonable fee for producing those additional copies. You can contact us for this purpose using our details in the “Contact” section below.

_**Your right to rectification:**_ If the personally identifiable information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to have it rectified. If we have shared your personally identifiable information with others, we’ll let them know about the rectification where possible. If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we will also tell you who we’ve shared your personally identifiable information with so that you can contact them directly.

_**Your right to erasure:**_ You can ask us to delete or remove your personally identifiable information in some circumstances, such as where we no longer need it or where you withdraw your consent (where applicable). If we have shared your personally identifiable information with others, we will let them know about the erasure where possible. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personally identifiable information with so that you can contact them directly.

_**Your right to restrict processing:**_ You can ask us to block or suppress the processing of your personally identifiable information in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of that personally identifiable information or you object to us processing it. It won’t stop us from storing your personally identifiable information, though. We will tell you before we lift any restriction. If we have shared your personally identifiable information with others, we will let them know about the restriction where it is possible for us to do so. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personally identifiable information with so that you can contact them directly.

_**Your right to data portability:**_ You have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personally identifiable information you have provided to us (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere or to ask us to transfer it to a third party of your choice.

_**Your right to object:**_ You can ask us to stop processing your personally identifiable information, and we will do so, if we are: (i) relying on our own or someone else’s legitimate interest to process your personally identifiable information, except if we can demonstrate compelling legal grounds for the processing; or (ii) processing your personally identifiable information for the purposes of direct marketing.

_**Your rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling:**_ You have the right not to be subject to a decision when it is based on automatic processing, including profiling, if it produces a legal effect or similarly significantly affects you, unless such profiling is necessary for the entering into, or the performance of, a contract between you and us.

_**Your right to withdraw consent:**_ If we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personally identifiable information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. You can exercise your right of withdrawal by contacting us using our details in the “Contact” section below or by using any other opt-out mechanism we may provide, such as an unsubscribe link in an email.

_**Your right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority:**_ If you have a concern about any aspect of our privacy practices, including the way we have handled your personally identifiable information, please contact us using our details in the “Contact” section below. You can also report any issues or concerns to your local supervisory authority. You can find a list of contact details for all EU supervisory authorities at: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm.>

If you would like to exercise any of your rights referred to above, this can be done by emailing us at [info@hamiltonmusical.com](mailto:info@hamiltonmusical.com).

Please note that while we will endeavour to make the updates as promptly as possible, communications may be sent using the original details until the changes have been processed.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

Please review this Privacy Policy from time to time. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Policy at any time. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy means you accept such changes. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we may provide you with additional forms of notice, as appropriate.

**Opt-out Process**

To opt-out of any future promotional messages from us, click here to [UNSUBSCRIBE](https://app2.easysendy.com/lists/vh641rzpt1f80/unsubscribe).

We will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. However, we are not responsible for removing your personally identifiable information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided with your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or your consent.

**IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EEA:** please also see the sub-section entitled “Your Rights” in the “Additional Information and Rights applicable to Individuals Located in the EEA” above.

#### Terms of Use

This Privacy Policy, and the use of the Website, is subject to our [Terms of Use](https://hamiltonmusical.com/eu-terms/).

**United States of America**

Our Website is maintained in the United States of America. By accessing the Website from a jurisdiction outside of the United States, you freely and specifically give us your consent to export your personally identifiable information from your local jurisdiction to our servers in the United States and to store and use such information in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EEA:** please also see the sub-section entitled “Transfers of your Personally Identifiable Information Outside the EEA” in the “Additional Information and Rights applicable to Individuals Located in the EEA” above.

**Contact**

For questions or concerns relating to Privacy Policy or your information, we can be contacted at: [info@hamiltonmusical.com](mailto:info@hamiltonmusical.com).

**Effective Date**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 24, 2018.
